迈克 · 诺斯: 首先，让我自我介绍一下，我叫迈克。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: First,
let me introduce myself, my name is Mike.
我在 LinkedIn 工作,
And I work at LinkedIn,
有两件事让我成为一个很好的人来和你谈论打字稿。
where two things I do make me a great
person to talk to you about TypeScript.
第一，我负责开发人员培训项目，所以
Number one,
I run the developer training program, so
我是公司的车间讲师。
I am a workshop instructor for
the company.
我帮助那里所有的工程师升级,
Where I help level up all of
all of the engineers there,
在各种主题数组中，包括打字稿。
in a various array of topics,
including TypeScript.
第二我是前端技术的领军人物,
And number two,
I am a tech lead on the front-end stack,
我主要关注的是打字稿的采用，对吗？
where I predominantly focus on
TypeScript adoption, right?
如果团队希望在他们的项目中使用 TypeScript,
On making it so that if teams wish to
use TypeScript with their project,
一切工作顺利，文档工具工作正常
everything works smoothly, and
the documentation tools work, and
所有的线条都很好。
all of the linting works nicely.
所以我一直深陷在这个领域
So I have been knee-deep in this area,
and I'm so
很高兴能在这里与大家分享我所学到的很多东西。
happy to be here to share a lot
of what I've learned with you.
所以首先，在我们跳进去之前，我们要弄脏我们的手
So first, before we jump in, and
we're gonna get our hands dirty
非常快，大约10分钟。
really quickly here,
within about 10 minutes.
让我们首先确定什么是打字稿，这样我们就知道会发生什么。
Let's first pin down exactly what
TypeScript is, so we know what to expect.
所以它主要是一种开源编程语言,
So it's an open-source
programming language, primarily,
它由微软的一个核心开发团队负责维护。
it's maintained by a core team
of developers at Microsoft.
它是 JavaScript 的一个类型化的语法超集。
And it's a typed,
syntactic superset of JavaScript.
这意味着，如果你采用打字稿的语法,
What that means is,
if you take TypeScript syntax,
你可以在其中看到 JavaScript 的语法。
you can kind of see
JavaScript's syntax within it.
这并不意味着每个 JavaScript 程序都可以快乐地工作
It does not mean that every
JavaScript program can happily
在没有任何错误的情况下运行打字稿编译器。
run through the TypeScript
compiler without any errors.
所以有时候人们会对此感到困惑。
So there is sometimes
confusion about that.
现在，如果你松开打字稿编译器,
Now, it's true that if you loosen
up the TypeScript compiler,
把它设置成最灵活的模式,
and kind of set it in the most
flexible possible mode,
很多普通的 JavaScript 程序都可以让它开心。
a lot of regular JavaScript
programs can make it happy.
但是使用一个非常灵活的动态类型，你可以做一些固有的事情
But there are inherently things you can do
with a really flexible, dynamically typed
类似 JavaScript 这样的语言，它永远不会让强类型语言开心。
language like JavaScript, that will never
make a strongly typed language happy.
编译成可读的 JavaScript，以及
TypeScript compiles to
readable JavaScript, and
它没有运行时部分，没有运行时组件。
it has no runtime part,
no runtime component.
这对您来说意味着类型在构建步骤中消失。
What that means to you is that
the types disappear in a build step.
你几乎可以把它想象成一个静态分析工具
So you're just really, you can almost
think of it like a static analysis tool
对你的代码库做了很多检查。
that does a lot of
checking on your codebase.
但是，当您有了要发送给您的用户的构建，或者
But when you have that build that
you're sending to your users, or
你用的是 Node.js 吗？
that you're running in Node.js?
除非你做一些很有异国情调的后空翻,
Unless you do some
really exotic backflips,
没有类型检查。
none of that type-checking is there.
这在某些方面是好的，但在其他方面是坏的。
And that's good in some ways,
and that's bad in other ways.
这很好，因为在运行时没有成本，对吧,
It's good in that there's
no cost at runtime, right,
这不会影响你的应用程序。
it's not gonna slow your app down.
运行时类型检查,
Runtime type-checking,
这是每个浏览器中每个用户都要运行的额外代码。
that's extra code that every user in
every browser is gonna be running.
因此，在构建步骤中消失打字稿是好事。
So TypeScript disappearing in
a build step is good there.
当然，当你接收到一些数据的时候,
But of course, when you're
receiving some data from a fetch,
还是你从用户那里得到了信息？
or you're getting some input from a user?
重要的是要明白，实际上并没有类型检查
It's important to understand that
there's really no type-checking that's
因为在这一点上，它只是一个 JavaScript 程序。
gonna happen there, because at that point,
it's just a JavaScript program.
所以这个项目有三个内容。
So the project kinda has
three things inside of it.
这是编程语言本身，这是语言服务器。
There's the programming language itself,
there's the language server.
这个程序可以给你的文本编辑器提供很多好东西
Which is a program that kind of feeds
your text editor a lot of great
这些信息可以在自动完成和
information that can manifest
itself in auto-completes and
工具提示，当你悬停在各种东西。
tool tips,
as you hover over various things.
语言服务器是一种你可以查询的东西,
The language server is sort of
something that you can query about,
我的程序现在怎么样了？
what's going on with my
program at this point?
然后是编译器，它是由语言服务器使用的。
And then there's the compiler, and
that is used by the language server.
但它实际上执行的是类型检查，并且
But it is what actually
performs the type-checking, and
这是获取打字稿文件和发送 JavaScript 文件的一种方式。
it is one way of taking TypeScript
files and emitting JavaScript files.
一个巨大的进步伴随着巴别塔7，巴别塔就是让我们带走的东西
A huge advancement that came along with
Babel 7, and Babel's what's let us take
现代的 JavaScript，并且有点浓缩，这样 Internet Explorer 就可以运行它了。
modern JavaScript, and kind of boil it
down so that Internet Explorer can run it.
所以你只需要简单地说出你关心哪些浏览器
And so you can just simply state
which browsers you care about and
你得到了一些相容的东西。
you get something compatible.
现在 Babel 可以将打字稿文件作为输入。
Babel can now take
TypeScript files as inputs.
现在，重要的是要理解这里不涉及类型检查。
Now, it's important to understand that
no type-checking is involved in there.
基本上知道打字稿代码的哪些部分可以被吃掉
Babel kind of just knows which parts
of the TypeScript code it can eat and
忽略，只留下 JavaScript。
ignore, leaving only
the JavaScript behind.
因此，您肯定希望与 Babel 并排使用打字稿编译器。
So you definitely wanna use the TypeScript
compiler side-by-side with Babel.
但最重要的进步是,
But the important advancement there is,
你有一个工具负责创建你的 JS 文件。
you have one piece of tooling that's
responsible for creating your JS files.
你不必担心，TypeScript 是如何表示一个类的
You don't have to worry about,
how does TypeScript represent a class for
Internet Explorer？
Internet Explorer?
巴别塔是如何表示它的呢? 这里会有碰撞吗
How does Babel represent it, and
is there gonna be a collision there, so
你可以很好地保证一致性。
you can have a great
assurance of consistency.
几乎可以把打字稿编译器想象成一个非常漂亮的连接器,
And almost think of the TypeScript
compiler as a really fancy linter,
或者其他静态分析工具来验证
or another static analysis tool
that just kind of verifies that
一切看起来都很好，但实际上并没有产生产量。
everything looks good, but
doesn't actually produce output.
因此，由于我教授了这门课程的最后一个版本,
So since I taught the last version
of this course for Frontend Masters,
在2017年，我们看到下载量增加了300% 。
which was in 2017,
we've seen a 300% increase in downloads.
我们可以看到，这是底部的每月下载图表。
And we can see, this is a monthly
download graph on the bottom.
我们可以看到它的基本匹配反应,
We can see that it's
basically matched React,
就流行程度和普及程度而言。
in terms of popularity and
prevalence of use.
所以 NPM 每年都做一个调查，他们要求受访者,
So NPM does a survey every year,
and they ask their respondents,
你用的是什么样的 javascript 语言？
what flavor of a JavaScript-y
language do you use?
或者你使用 ES6，ES5，或者打字稿？
CoffeeScript, or do you use ES6,
or ES5, or TypeScript?
结果显示，46% 的受访者认为，在某些方面，或者说在某些方面
And it turns out, 46% of respondents
said that in some part or
他们的另一个程序，他们使用打字稿。
another of their programming,
they make use of TypeScript.
如果你看看 NPM 中的所有软件包,
And if you look at all
of the packages in NPM,
超过40% 的用户声明打字稿为依赖项或 devDependency。
over 40% of them declare TypeScript
as a dependency or devDependency.
所以你可能正在使用它，即使你不认为你正在使用它。
So you're probably using it,
even if you don't think you're using it.
你用的是这种打印语言,
You're using something that's
written in this typed language,
根据类型检查。
and depending on that type-checking.
而且，你可以潜在地利用这种类型的信息。
And potentially, you could take
advantage of that type information.